Please stop streaming with a banal
webcam rectangle. You can
spend literally 5 minutes, including
watching this video, and transform your
camera on the
stream. Hello everyone, my name is Grus, and I have
five plugins for you that will
visually transform your camera on the
stream, and the first such plugin I bet
you've already heard of it. This is Advanced Masks.
Follow the link in the description, click
download, and select Windows Installer. I
always tend to choose Windows
Installer simply because it's more convenient.
You don't have to bother
dragging and dropping files somewhere,
click download, download the archive in the archive,
run OBS Advanced Mask Installer, and
without changing anything, install it in the
folder where it usually suggests.
This will also apply to the
plugins that we will discuss
further. They all install in the desired
folder. Find where you have OBS installed
on absolutely any source.
Right-click, add filters, and
Advanced Mask. By default, for some
reason, it sets the size to 800 by 600, but we
can give our camera our own size,
which  We are set in the settings in
my case 1.20 by 1080 we got
this size of our camera And then we
can make it, say, square
cut at the edges we can center it
so that we better get into the frame For
example, for a game scene I make a
vertical camera like this since I am
sitting A little off-center
shift the X axis a little and going down below we
can round the corners of our camera it will
be best seen if we add a
background color set some color and
lower it in OBS below the source with the camera
Now you can see how we have all this
customizable corner radius we customize for
ourselves if here we choose not uniform but
Custom we can even customize each corner
separately for example we need to have
only the upper left and
upper right be rounded And at the bottom Let's say
we want to place Well, I don't know
there a fundraiser a thermometer may sometimes
require But I just
throw it in like that we will need to place the
camera right at the edge of the screen Here,
accordingly, we can not round the left corners
but round only the right ones the
main thing is to make sure that our
rounding parameters in pixels are  the same
so that it somehow looks visually interesting
and so on here is already to
your taste and color I usually make a uniform
and just
round off that the webcam is still
wide enough and can, like during the
game, for example, cover the interface with it
in the game I want to make it
narrower somewhere we’ll leave it like this,
reduce it and place it somewhere where we
like on our stream on our stage
I will obviously show it on a
larger version You can
make your webcam smaller If you want to
add some kind of frame to your webcam,
you can, for example, add it in the same way
as I added the background
color, let’s call it frame and choose something
Well, to
contrast something more strongly like this, for
example Okay, using the Advanced
Mask filter that we used for the camera
We can also right-click on the frame with the
Advanced Mask filters Okay and here
we can round it off ourselves
focusing on the degree of angles that
we made for our camera Or we can
just select Mask Type
Source here and
specify our camera as the source That’s it,
our background color has acquired exactly the
same shape that  and our camera, we will only have to
set the required size and
place the source. Under the
camera source, we equalize a little more,
you can specify some more contrasting color and Black, then it
will look something like yours, not
rejected by your camera, you can come
up with all sorts of jokes there, you can
apply a color correction filter to the frame with the camera
and make it a little
more
transparent, let's say I want to leave
some color like this if we
go to the filters of our frame, let's
play a little with the Advanced
Mask filter. In particular, I would remove the binding to
the shape of the camera, leave it, set the size to
19920 by 1080 and insert the corner radius the
same, for example, as our camera 60
pixels. Next, we crop the whole thing in width.
For a more detailed adjustment of the
size, you can use these
arrows and this is some kind of frame
we get, it's clear what I'm doing now
for demonstration. You have it yourself. Adjust it
more precisely so that both here and here the
thickness of the frame does not differ. If you don't
like it and it's a
banal frame, you can add
Gradient filter for this we install the
gradient Source plugin in the same way
download select Windows Installer the
installation principle is always the same We
first close our OBS if we have it
open and run the Installer downloaded from the link in the
description then reopen
OBS and in our sources you can
right-click to select Gradient
add the
Gradient source specify some first
color specify the second color
and now we have two colors from one
smoothly transitions to another after which
we return to our original
Advanced Mask plugin Go to filters
on the gradient add Advanced Mask I
would, for example, use the rotation slider
to flip it like this by 90 ° Well and according to our
old scheme we adjust the width height and
round off When we have from one color
as if smoothly transitions to another and all
this as you see literally in two clicks
and another trick for you piggy bank look
Well add some background by the way you
can download backgrounds from my boost if
anything they are there make the background full
screen add screen capture here Well
or a game or some other content it
doesn't matter  we place it so that there
is approximately the same number
of pixels from top to bottom, add our camera on top and
using filters, the same Advanced
Mask applied to the
camera, we can select the
Gradient option here. This is the same Gradient.
In our case, we will naturally flip it
using the rotation slider, flip it the
other way by
180°, adjust the degree of this
edge blur, adjust the position, and
using the position slider,
we can make such a smooth transition
between the camera and the content
that we
broadcast. What else can be done
interesting with our camera? Well, for example,
add a 3D effect. I talked about this
plugin in one of the previous videos about the
plugins that I use. In the same way,
download, download, install, we won’t even
dwell on this for long. If
everything is installed correctly, you
will see this
3D effect filter in your filters. Previously, it was part of the
streamfx FX plugin package. It became paid, and now
someone has helped you get it. I honestly
don’t know the names of all these wonderful
people who make plugins. Someone
made a wonderful separate 3D
effect plugin. We can impose something. I
thought, why?  I have a webcam in the
lower right corner, I have this, we
will work with it, you can see me here.
Hello. We can apply a 3D effect filter
to our camera, but it will be easier to combine
our frame that we have already created, it was not for nothing that
we created it, and combine ours like this, by
selecting, holding Control on the
keyboard, group the selected
objects and call it a camera group,
for example, you can naturally name it in your
own way, and we apply this 3D effect filter
to the group. What we can
do here is we can rotate our camera
a little,
tilt the
Y axis, rotate it like this. If something is
wrong, you can always reset it to default. For
example, considering that I am
looking at the content that is being broadcast, it is a
game, a clip, a movie, it does not matter. I would rotate
myself a little along the Y axis like this,
make it a little sideways. In
principle, I always advise everyone to
position themselves. If you are sitting
sideways. If you are not directly in front of the camera,
position yourself towards the content. It’s just that
sometimes it looks strange when
people position themselves. For example,
they have a camera like this, something is happening here, a
game, for example.  And they themselves are looking at the edge of
the screen, this is strange. Well, you can always,
even if your angle does not
allow you to place the camera differently, you
can always apply a transformation to your camera and
flip it horizontally.
Nothing bad happened. You
just flipped your webcam and now you
are looking towards the content, but you don’t want to
flip the camera. You can always
just move it to the other side if you
are sitting. No way, I’m looking in the other direction, and I’ll flip it
again. Now I’ll flip it
horizontally. Well, no one is stopping
you from placing the webcam somewhere on the right side of the screen. In the upper right corner, in the lower right corner, somewhere in the middle. Well, again, no one is forcing you to sit somewhere
on the left side of the screen. You are free to do whatever you
want with your webcam. Well, with the 3D
effect, I think it’s clear. On my
stream, using the 3D effect, I expanded
the chat like this. What else can we do with our
camera? We have STR Glow Shadow plugins.
Again, we find the Windows Installer at the link.
This plugin can
add a shadow to any object, any
source. In this case, I’m disabling ours.
Gradient And
they throw a
Shadow on the camera again, I'll temporarily turn on the background
color so that it's better to see what's
going on with us, and here, using
the sliders, we can adjust whether we have a
shadow outside the object or whether it will be
inside the object,
then we can adjust the size of this
shadow by playing with the sliders,
for example, I like the shadow from this side,
again, it gives some kind of volume to
our image, at least you
will clearly differ from thousands of thousands of
streamers with banal rectangular
webcams. The next plugin I'll
tell you about is background removal to
remove the background behind you, click go to download
and, as usual, select Windows
Installer here. Yes, this is an analogue of NVIDIA broadcast,
which many people use. For example, I'm not a
fan of NVIDIA broadcast, at least
because it's third-party software, it hangs in
your tray, it eats up resources, at least
it crashes. There are a lot of cases in my
consultations when people contact me and
say I can't turn on the camera
or my microphone has fallen off, and
NVIDIA broadcast, for those who don't know, is
responsible for both microphone filters and
camera filters, but all this
happens as if not in  OBS and on the side
in third-party software I somehow got used to it is
more convenient for me to do everything within the OBS framework,
therefore, having installed background removal on
our camera in the filters, we add
background removal where it
works for us. This, as you can see, is also a VSRATO
like NVIDIA broadcast if you have a
non-uniform background behind you, naturally,
this will be Somehow, anyhow, we can, of
course, go to the advanced settings and
play with the sliders, we can
set it up like this for clarity,
we can adjust the threshold of the
contour filter to remove the background more effectively,
you will be able to do it if it is uniform.
That is, you have fewer objects in the frame
than I do, ideally, generally a chroma key there is
some kind of green background or you are sitting in front of
some plain wallpaper and so
on. In this case, you will be able to more
effectively remove your background, among other
things. Now I have the light on so that
the picture looks adequately somehow. I have a
TV on there, backlighting, backlighting.
Light. If it is dark behind you, then
you will be able to remove your background even better.
If you are illuminated in the frame  and the objects in the back are
all dark, but I'm showing you this
filter not so much to remove
your background as to blur
it. Because all these artifacts.
When we can't quite keep up with us,
this plugin can be avoided if we
add a blur filter here. Then
our background is not completely removed, but
simply blurred. Firstly, I'll say right away that
it consumes less resources. When we simply
blur our background, we get a kind of
bokeh effect from behind, like on expensive
cameras with expensive lenses. The advantage of
this method is that if you are somehow...
Not ideal, for example, my shoulder is
blurred if you are not perfectly removed from the
background. It's okay, it still
looks somehow adequate, plus or minus. With
this
slider, we adjust the degree of
blurring of the background. If we
try too hard to add naturalness,
it looks somehow inadequate. But
if just a little bit,
literally by one, by two, by three, then
it already looks interesting.
Some depth appears in the frame.
Some kind of effect appears. Well, a slightly more
expensive picture, as if we  We shoot with an
expensive camera and with
the help of this pseudo-
Bouquet effect we can
make a more interesting picture even with a banal cheap webcam.
In general, I showed you the filter. Do with
it what you want. It's just that many are like: Oh, there's a
mess behind me. Oh, there are children
running behind me. I want to cut out the background. You
can't cut it out perfectly. If you
want it to be perfect, then you need
good light and a chroma key, preferably. Yes, a
green or blue uniform background. I'm still
against chroma key in chroma key, but that's in the
past. I
streamed with chroma key in 2015 and 2016. I'm still for
showing your apartment, your backdrop.
If something is in the way behind you, well,
somehow change the angle so that you don't
get extra objects in the frame from behind.
For example, there's a bed, a
sofa, a dog sleeping there, of course. I
just picked the angle I needed. But
if there's no way at all
to position the camera in such a way. So that there's something
interesting behind you, you have  In
the apartment, you can use this
filter, at least try to blur the
background. Of course, the
filters presented in this video can be
combined with each other. You can
turn on the same Gradient frame
that we made. I disabled it for clarity.
But I can turn on both the
shadow and cropping. The correct order of
filters also matters. If, for
example, you want the background to be
removed, and the corners to be rounded, and
some shape to be set in the background, then we remove
the background by simply holding down Ctrl on the keyboard and using the
arrow keys, we move
up. That is, we first remove the
background on our camera, and then apply the
ADV Mask filter to round the corners and
set the shape of the webcam. We can also
turn on Shadow, our shadow, and turn off
Gradient. Now we have three filters applied to the camera:
background blur, shadow, and ADV Mask for
rounding the corners. I promised five plugins as a bonus.
I'll tell you about the Wave for plugin.
This is a plugin for audio visualization.
I talked about it in one of my previous videos. Click the
go to download button here. We
need to download setup
EX.  Downloaded, installed, go to OBS, in the
sources panel, either click the plus sign or
right-click to add an audio
visualizer.
We select, for example, our
microphone as a source, and we already have this visualizer.
As you can see, it reacts to when we
speak. We can place it like this
on the camera. We can use the
transform tool to right-click on the
source, flip it vertically, and
place it somewhere like this at the bottom,
for example, so that these edges are not
visible. We can place the source visualizer
under the camera group, and now
when we speak, our visualizer
reacts to our voice. Naturally, it does
not necessarily have to be linked to
our microphone. We can link it to a
music source, and so on.
I talked about it again in one of the previous
videos. Here is a selection
of plugins that will help you somehow
visually transform your camera on the
stream. I remind you that if you suddenly experience
any difficulties, you
can order a consultation from me at the link in the description below.
You will also find
links to all the plugins from this video there. You will also
find a link to my boost Telegram
channel. Subscribe. Be sure to. And
you had a load with you.  See you Kid
[music]